A Guide to the InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia Records, 1978-2007
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia Records, 1978-2007
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-79
0.75 linear feet
The InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia Records span the years 1978-2007 and contains newsletters, bylaws, newspaper articles, member rosters, treasurer's reports, photographs, negatives, CD-ROMs with digital photos, and a magnetic scrapbook.
The InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Donated by Albert L. Leightey, President of the Interservice Club Council of Fairfax, in October 2021.
Historical and Biographical Information
In December 1977, Charles W. Mowery organized The InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia. Mowery was inspired to establish a council of service organizations after speaking to other service organizations as the Past International Director for the Fairfax Host Lions Club. He became the Council’s first president.
The objectives of the organization are to promote friendship, coordinate projects, and discuss and improve upon community problems among member organizations. The Council also gives to charitable organizations and promotes cooperation with the Fairfax City government, George Mason University, the Chamber of Commerce and City of Fairfax Regional Library.
Membership is restricted to organizations within the City of Fairfax and surrounding vicinity. The Council was originally comprised of 11 organization including the Optimist, Kiwanis, Rotary, Civitans, Jaycees, American Association of University Women, the Women’s Club of Fairfax, Lions, Lioness, The Salvation Army Auxiliary, and the Fairfax Hospital Auxiliary. The signature event of the Council is an annual Volunteer Recognition and Celebration which recognizes exceptional volunteers of the member organizations. As of 2022, the Council is comprised of 25 member organizations.
Scope and Content
The InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia Records span the years 1978-2007 and contains newsletters, bylaws, newspaper articles, member rosters, treasurer's reports, photographs, negatives, CD-ROMs with digital photos, and a magnetic scrapbook. The magnetic scrapbook contains photographs, correspondence, news clippings, and other ephemera related to the Council’s work.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Fairfax (Va.) - History; The InterService Club Council of Fairfax, Virginia
Container List
- Annual Selection of Volunteers Policy, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- City Volunteer Night, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ISCC Bylaws, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ISCC History, 1980-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Newsletter, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newsletter, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newsletter, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newsletter, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newsletter, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newsletter, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newsletter, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newsletter, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newsletter Layout Materials, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Past Presidents (1978-1999), Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Policy on City Entrance Signs, 1980-2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Press, 1978-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Rosters, 1994-2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Treasurer's Reports, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 1996 “Volunteers of the Year”, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 1998 “Volunteers of the Year”, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 2000 “Volunteers of the Year”, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 2001 “Volunteers of the Year”, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- 2002 “Volunteers of the Year” [includes photos and negatives], 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 2003 “Volunteers of the Year”, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- 2004 “Volunteers of the Year” [CD-ROM and photos], 2004 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- 2005 “Volunteers of the Year” [CD-ROM], 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 2006 “Volunteers of the Year”, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Magnetic album scrapbook, 1978-1997 (Box 2)